<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Practical Spiral Dynamics on Save The World</title>
    <link>https://stwi.blog/save-the-world/growing-up/practical-spiral-dynamics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Practical Spiral Dynamics on Save The World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 05:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stwi.blog/save-the-world/growing-up/practical-spiral-dynamics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Field Guide</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/save-the-world/growing-up/practical-spiral-dynamics/field-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/save-the-world/growing-up/practical-spiral-dynamics/field-guide/</guid>
      <description>How do we know what color level someone or a group is at? To figure this out there are some questions we need to answer:
Are they more individual focused (tick) or group focused (tock)? What do they know to be True? What are they willing to die for? Let&amp;rsquo;s go through the color levels again, but this time asking those questions.
Beige (FirstAwakening) At Beige focus is on the individual family (tick).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blindspots</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/save-the-world/growing-up/practical-spiral-dynamics/blindspots/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/save-the-world/growing-up/practical-spiral-dynamics/blindspots/</guid>
      <description>Everyone has blind spots. Except me. I don&amp;rsquo;t have any. This deeply amuses me because it is so obviously false, and yet there is a part of me that really believes it. After all I can&amp;rsquo;t see my own blind spots so obviously I don&amp;rsquo;t have any, right? In other words, I don&amp;rsquo;t know what I don&amp;rsquo;t know. But this is true for everyone. We all can not see our own blind spots by definition!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shadows</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/save-the-world/growing-up/practical-spiral-dynamics/shadows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/save-the-world/growing-up/practical-spiral-dynamics/shadows/</guid>
      <description>All of the stages come with both gifts and shadows. I will touch on the shadow side first. The part that is hurting and not working well. The part that is causing harm in the world.
Beige Thee shadow version of this stage is what happens when we collapse down to survival mode. Only me and mine matter. Just like one of those Zombie apocalypse everyone else is just a monster to be dealt with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gifts</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/save-the-world/growing-up/practical-spiral-dynamics/gifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/save-the-world/growing-up/practical-spiral-dynamics/gifts/</guid>
      <description>Each stage brings a crucial gift. But we can have blindspots here too. For example, Green hates Red and can see nothing useful in the Red mindset whatsoever. And similarly Red hates Green. To be sure, Green is not wrong. We are in fact living in a world of systemic racism and sexism. But what Green (and I have to admit I too) struggle with is to realize there actually is a gift that Red brings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/save-the-world/growing-up/practical-spiral-dynamics/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/save-the-world/growing-up/practical-spiral-dynamics/resources/</guid>
      <description>Before finishing this section I want to share some history resources. Although Spiral Dynamics is a story, there is real historical context to all of these stages. I hope I have inspired interest in this story of where we came from. If you are at all interested in learning more about any of the stages I strongly urge you to dig in and learn its history first. I am a book person so my recommendations are all books, but I know not everyone is so if you know of a good documentary or movie please send it to me so I can include it here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards Turquoise</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/save-the-world/growing-up/practical-spiral-dynamics/towards-turqoise/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/save-the-world/growing-up/practical-spiral-dynamics/towards-turqoise/</guid>
      <description>When I first started telling people the Spiral Dynamics story I hoped it would wake them up to Turquoise all by it self. But nope. Most people are not quite ready yet. I feel like a popcorn kernel that has popped a little earlier than the rest. I hope and pray that it is just a matter of time before the rest of the kernels start popping so I can nestle in with them, but in the meantime it looks like I have some work to do.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
