<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Practical Spiral Dynamics on Save The World</title>
    <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/practical-spiral-dynamics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Practical Spiral Dynamics on Save The World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 05:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/practical-spiral-dynamics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Field Guide</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/practical-spiral-dynamics/field-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/practical-spiral-dynamics/field-guide/</guid>
      <description>How do we know what color level someone or a group is at? To figure this out there are some questions we need to answer:
 Are they more individual focused (tick) or group focused (tock)? What do they know to be True? What are they willing to die for?  Let&amp;rsquo;s go through the color levels again, but this time asking those questions.
Beige (FirstAwakening) At Beige focus starts on the individual family (tick).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spiral Dynamics</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/practical-spiral-dynamics/gifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/practical-spiral-dynamics/gifts/</guid>
      <description>Purple Imagine you have been hiking mostly alone in the wilderness for months. You are carrying a heavy pack and it hurts. You have lost most of your toenails. And yet day in and day out you keep on going. Why? Because there is a desparate need for healing. A healing that only nature can provide. And then one day you find yourself.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blindspots</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/practical-spiral-dynamics/examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/practical-spiral-dynamics/examples/</guid>
      <description>I find it quite amusing that everyone except me has blind spots. I don&amp;rsquo;t have any. This is so obviously, amusingly false, and yet there is a part of me that really believes it. After all I can&amp;rsquo;t see my own blind spots so obviously I don&amp;rsquo;t have any, right? In other words, I don&amp;rsquo;t know what I don&amp;rsquo;t know. But this is true for everyone. We all can not see our own blind spots by definition!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
