<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Practical Spiral Dynamics on Save The World</title>
    <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/practical-spiral-dynamics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Practical Spiral Dynamics on Save The World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 05:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/practical-spiral-dynamics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Field Guide</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/practical-spiral-dynamics/field-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/practical-spiral-dynamics/field-guide/</guid>
      <description>How do we know what color level someone or a group is at? To figure this out there are some questions we need to answer:
 Are they more individual focused (tick) or group focused (tock)? What do they know to be True? What are they willing to die for?  Let&amp;rsquo;s go through the color levels again, but this time asking those questions.
Beige (FirstAwakening) At Beige focus starts on the individual family (tick).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blindspots</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/practical-spiral-dynamics/blindspots/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/practical-spiral-dynamics/blindspots/</guid>
      <description>Everyone has blind spots. Except me. I don&amp;rsquo;t have any. This is so obviously, amusingly false, and yet there is a part of me that really believes it. After all I can&amp;rsquo;t see my own blind spots so obviously I don&amp;rsquo;t have any, right? In other words, I don&amp;rsquo;t know what I don&amp;rsquo;t know. But this is true for everyone. We all can not see our own blind spots by definition!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shadows</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/practical-spiral-dynamics/shadows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/practical-spiral-dynamics/shadows/</guid>
      <description>All of the stages come with both gifts and shadows. I will touch on the shadow side first. The part that is hurting and not working well. The part that is causing harm in the world.
Beige The shadow version of this stage is simple survival. We all are at this stage from time to time, the question is how long we stay here. For example, when I have a bad flu my world collapses down to simply surviving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gifts</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/practical-spiral-dynamics/gifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/practical-spiral-dynamics/gifts/</guid>
      <description>Each stage brings a crucial gift. But we can have blindspots here too. For example, Green hates Red and can see nothing useful in the Red mindset whatsoever. And similarily Red hates Green. To be sure, Green is not wrong. We are in fact living in a world of systemic racism and sexism. But what Green (and I have to admit I too) struggle with is to realize there actually is a gift that Red brings.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
