<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Healing Up on Save The World</title>
    <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Healing Up on Save The World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 05:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nonviolence</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/non-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/non-violence/</guid>
      <description>As I write this bombs are falling on Ukranian homes. Families are huddled in subways just trying to survive, and millions upon millions of people have fled the country. We cheer as we watch the Ukranians bravely fight back against what seem hopeless odds. Sometimes there is no choice but to meet violence with violence. In World War II most of the world had collapsed into authoritarian Red. The only thing that saved us was armed conflict; nothing else would do against Hitler and Tojo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truth</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/truth/</guid>
      <description>We need to find our truth before we can heal. Hakomi gently guides clients deeper and deeper into a non ordinary state of consciousness that helps them get all the way down to their core beliefs. These are the (mostly) unconscious beliefs people have about how the world works. What is and is not safe. These beliefs are usually created by a child desperately trying to survive against unfair odds. So we honor the genius of that child for finding something that worked, but then help them see how that solution also has come with a price.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mindfulness</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/mindfulness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/mindfulness/</guid>
      <description>There is a lot of truly great writing about mindfulness. For example, Mark Manson has an excellent article here. He writes in his vivid way of all the amazing benefits both health-wise and mental. But in that article he lightly touches upon something that is often overlooked. We tend to think of meditation as the only way to cultivate mindfulness. It is not. Meditation is not the answer to all our problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mind/Body</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/mind-body/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/mind-body/</guid>
      <description>We have this weird illusion that somehow our body is separate from our mind. As if they are separate things. What a strange story we tell ourselves. It is so not true. What happens in our body affects our Mind. What happens in our Mind affects our body. It is all one. When we suffer a traumatic event we store that trauma somewhere in our body. In his book The body keeps the score, the psychiatrist Bessel van der Kolk talks about how when he first started out as a therapist working with traumatized people, his profession didn&amp;rsquo;t have much to offer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organicity</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/organicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/organicity/</guid>
      <description>I don’t think people are seeking the meaning of life as much as they are seeking the experience of being alive.” Joseph Campbell
 &amp;ldquo;Organicity&amp;rdquo; is an unfamiliar, awkward word, and I have to confess I initially resisted it. But that resistance was mostly because it is awkward to learn something truly new. Ignore what the dictionary might say, in this sense the word combines &amp;ldquo;organism&amp;rdquo; with &amp;ldquo;icity&amp;rdquo; to mean the nature of an organism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/unity/</guid>
      <description>There is a certain connection magic that always comes up for a group that goes through something intense together. People connect and become one. It is part of being human. We are a deeply social animal and we are meant to form groups both large and small. We even have mirror neurons dedicated to this task. If someone is grieving I grieve too. If someone is in pain I hurt also.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/change/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/change/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loving Presence</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/love/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/love/</guid>
      <description>“People will only protect what they love.” Jacques Coustea
 Love is the base. Everything has to be built on top of this. In Hakomi we were taught to build a loving &amp;ldquo;bubble&amp;rdquo; between ourselves and our client. In HAI it comes from the deep love from the facilitators and the team. They are all there because they are deeply committed to love and together they create the same &amp;ldquo;bubble&amp;rdquo; but for an entire room.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
