<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Healing Up on Save The World</title>
    <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Healing Up on Save The World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 05:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nonviolence</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/non-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/non-violence/</guid>
      <description>Huge acne cysts full of puss sprang up on my face at the end of my sophomore year in high school. They swelled so big that my skin was pulled painfully tight and made it hard to smile. They were almost as big as ping pong balls &amp;ndash; I am not exaggerating. And when they finally, finally popped they left very big, deep, pitted scars. And they kept on coming. I went from one of the cuter boys to one of the ugliest just like that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truth</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/truth/</guid>
      <description>In first grade I had my first spiritual experience. I was walking down a long corridor thinking about how I want to keep on doing good things while simultaneously feeling kind of embarrassed and hokey and suddenly the light coming in from the windows got very strong and I was walking into this welcoming, warm light wrapping all around me. Yes. This. I will always step into the light. Always. This is my most precious gift.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mindfulness</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/mindfulness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/mindfulness/</guid>
      <description>There is a lot of truly great writing about mindfulness. For example, Mark Manson has an excellent article here. He writes in his vivid way of all the amazing benefits both health-wise and mental. But in that article he lightly touches upon something that is often overlooked. We tend to think of meditation as the only way to cultivate mindfulness. It is not. Meditation is not the answer to all our problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mind/Body</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/mind-body/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/mind-body/</guid>
      <description>We have this weird illusion that somehow our body is different from our mind. As if they are separate things. What a strange story we tell ourselves. It is so not true. What happens in our body affects our mind. What happens in our mind affects our body. When we suffer a traumatic event we store that trauma somewhere in our body. When Bessel van der Kolk, author of The Body Keeps the Score, first started out as a psychiatrist his profession didn&amp;rsquo;t have much to offer traumatized people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organicity</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/organicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/organicity/</guid>
      <description>I don’t think people are seeking the meaning of life as much as they are seeking the experience of being alive.” Joseph Campbell
 &amp;ldquo;Organicity&amp;rdquo; is an unfamiliar, awkward word, and I have to confess I initially resisted it. My partner especially dislikes it but try as we might we can&amp;rsquo;t come up with an alternative. We really do need a new word here. Ignore what the dictionary might say, in this sense the word combines &amp;ldquo;organism&amp;rdquo; with &amp;ldquo;icity&amp;rdquo; to mean the nature of an organism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/change/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/change/</guid>
      <description>Change is messy and scary so we resist with all our might. But it is what we have to do. We can stay blocked for years and years, but organicity is always striving towards health and eventually something has to give. Let me give an example.
I was in Gautemala with my ex-wife for a month and midway through my testosterone prescription ran out. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get a refill but it turns out that Guatemalan pharmacies will sell you pretty much anything they have without the need for a prescription.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loving Presence</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/love/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/love/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;All human behavior is either an act of love or a cry for love&amp;rdquo; Stan Dale
  “The hardest to learn was the least complicated” Indigo Girls
 Let&amp;rsquo;s go back to Aaron Stark&amp;rsquo;s story about how he almost became a school shooter. What saved him? Simply a friend&amp;rsquo;s undemanding love. The friend wasn&amp;rsquo;t trying to fix him, he just wanted to spend time with him. Even though Aaron had lied to him and stolen from him, his friend was still there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/healing-up/unity/</guid>
      <description>There is a certain connection magic that always comes up for a group that goes through something intense together. People connect and become one. It is part of being human. We are a deeply social animal and we are meant to form groups both large and small. We even have mirror neurons dedicated to this task. If someone is grieving I grieve too. If someone is in pain I hurt also.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
