<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Save The World</title>
    <link>https://stwi.blog/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Save The World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 10:04:31 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stwi.blog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Everything is God</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/posts/everything-is-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 10:04:31 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/posts/everything-is-god/</guid>
      <description>Everything is God (the Universe) and God (the Universe) is love&amp;quot;
Does this ring true to you? It is the core belief of the various New Thought religions such as the Centers for Spiritual Living (CSL) . The truth of these words live in my full body not just my head. Back when I was still an atheist I spent many Sundays in CSL church standing in witness to the music and crying as I awoke to this deeper truth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eight is a magic number (tangent)</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/posts/eight/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/posts/eight/</guid>
      <description>Why is eight a magic number?
Valence shells Eight is a magic number in chemistry. When atoms combine into molecules they want to have exactly eight electrons in their outermost valence shell. Chemistry is based on this. It defines what atoms can join with what other atoms. So for example carbon atoms have 4 electrons in their outer valence shell and if you put two of them together that form a total of eight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022 Hike the Pacific Crest Trail</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/posts/pct-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/posts/pct-trip/</guid>
      <description>Backpack without a backpack on the Pacific Crest Trail (PCT). Join us for our first &amp;ldquo;comfy&amp;rdquo; backpacking trip. Experience the magical connection with nature that backpackers get without the need to actually carry a backpack and provisions.
How is this possible??
Each day you get to hike from one campground to the next. Our truck and trailer will transport the gear. At the next camp site your tent and hot meals await you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/posts/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 16:16:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/posts/resources/</guid>
      <description>Actualized.org
The Great Work, our way into the future https://thomasberry.org/quote/the-great-work-our-way-into-the-future/
recommended by Forest Bathing organization </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programmers Path</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/posts/programmers-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 16:16:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/posts/programmers-path/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m curious to know if there is interest in this. It is kind of an amusing thing to think about. How could engineers have anything to contribute to the conversation of waking up to a bigger consciousness? And yet I think we do.
Post a message if you might be interested in me writing this up. Right now I am focused on the main path and this is definitely not that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/posts/snippets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/posts/snippets/</guid>
      <description>collection of snippets Missing Loving Presence principle Love is scary, so we hold back. From the very first weekend of my Hakomi trainings we were taught to create a loving bubble with our client. If we could not find a way to love them it was suggested they should maybe not even be our client. So clearly Hakomi is grounded first and foremost in Love but it was not yet one of the principles.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
