<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Save The World</title>
    <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Save The World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 15:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>We need a plan</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/we-need-a-plan2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/we-need-a-plan2/</guid>
      <description>All of me, All of you, All of us. If I&amp;rsquo;m going to propose something so audacious as a plan to radically transform the world, it is going to require all of me. I can&amp;rsquo;t hold anything back. I need to bring in everything that I am. Not just the shiny parts I want to show to you, but all of my rage, sorrow and pain too. Not just the gifts that I have, but the broken hurting places too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hike the Pacific Crest Trail</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/pct-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/pct-trip/</guid>
      <description>Backpack without a backpack on the Pacific Crest Trail (PCT). Join us for our first &amp;ldquo;comfy&amp;rdquo; backpacking trip. Experience the magical connection with nature that backpackers get without the need to actually carry a backpack and provisions.
How is this possible??
Each day you get to hike from one campground to the next. Our truck and trailer will transport the gear. At the next camp site your tent and hot meals await you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 16:16:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/resources/</guid>
      <description>Actualized.org
Long winded intro on Spiral Dynamics.
 Great motivation talk at the beginning Transformational dilemma is great idea, but the actual ones offered are terrible Weak on history Completely misses the impact of agriculture https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=23aDNBvn_2g  The Great Work, our way into the future https://thomasberry.org/quote/the-great-work-our-way-into-the-future/
 recommended by Forest Bathing organization  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stone Soup1</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/stone-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 10:04:31 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/stone-soup/</guid>
      <description>Stone Soup &amp;ndash; stone soup text goes here &amp;mdash; edited</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programmers Path</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/programmers-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 16:16:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/programmers-path/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m curious to know if there is interest in this. It is kind of an amusing thing to think about. How could engineers have anything to contribute to the conversation of waking up to a bigger consciousness? And yet I think we do.
Post a message if you might be interested in me writing this up. Right now I am focused on the main path and this is definitely not that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Save the World</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/save-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 16:16:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/save-the-world/</guid>
      <description>I love movies where the reluctant heroes are desperately trying to save the world against what seem impossible odds. First they overcome their fears and limitations, and then they commit. Then they work through their bitter squabbles and commit to each other. I want to be like them. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping you do too, because the world is in desperate need of heroes right now.
Police kill black men seemingly at will.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spheres of compassion</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/we-need-a-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 16:16:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/we-need-a-plan/</guid>
      <description>But first we need a plan. Our current approach is not working. There are many things not working, but let me focus on climate change because it is a huge problem. Emissions keep on going up. World wide agreements are made, but never for enough and emissions keep on going up. Environmentalists pin their hope on elections but then the other party gets elected and dismantles previous work. And emissions keep on going up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/better-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/better-theory/</guid>
      <description>Better Theory. We now have a theory called Integral theory that brings in all of us not just our western, rational minds. It welcomes the scientist as well as the Buddhist, and it suggests a hopeful path of what wants to happen next. Better Therapy. We are now seeing proven, effective treatments for even people suffering with severe trauma. We&amp;rsquo;ve never had that before. Hurt people hurt people. If we can stop the cycle of suffering passed from one generation to the next that alone would dramatically change the world for the better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/civil-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/civil-war/</guid>
      <description>Let me start with a simple question. Why do we think the Civil War actually solved anything? Did that war really change hearts and minds? I don&amp;rsquo;t think so. Not really. Imagine the end of the U.S. Civil War. The North has just crushed the South using brutal, total war: Sherman&amp;rsquo;s March to the Sea. The South surrenders with the bitter realization that the North will stop at absolutely no unspeakable atrocity in order to totally crush them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/climate-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/climate-change/</guid>
      <description>In some ways we are already too late. We already have launched irreversible climate change. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean we are necessarily doomed, especially if we can rally to halt emissions in time. But it does mean that we are going to have to learn to cooperate in a way we have not before. Places that used to produce food will likely become barren with drought. But places that used to be too cold to grow food will suddenly become productive farmlands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/despair-to-hope/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/despair-to-hope/</guid>
      <description>It is a pretty wild ambition to save the world. To even have a chance it will require many, many different voices speaking from a place of deep Truth. We all have our own paths to Truth, let me first start with mine.
Save the World When I let my heart open wider and wider into the vastness of all that is, I find pain. So. much. pain! Can you feel it also?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/examples/</guid>
      <description>Orange to Green Crying Indian Commercial</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/hakomi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/hakomi/</guid>
      <description>Body-Centered Psychotherapy
   Old paradigm New paradigm     fundamental separateness unbroken wholeness
fundamental connectedness   absolute certitude
only matter is real (materialism) uncertainty, relativity
consciosness is real (dualistm, monism)   the mind/body split mind/body integration   biology is destingy we create our own destiny    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/snippets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/snippets/</guid>
      <description>My goal is to first save the world, because it needs saving. If we don&amp;rsquo;t stop carbon dioxide emissions soon, billions will die. But we have to go way beyond just that because in some ways it already is too late. Climate change is now irreversible. There is no going back. We are going to have to learn to share a very different, challenging world. Simply to survive we now have no choice but to learn to care for all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/trump/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/trump/</guid>
      <description>During the Trump presidency it felt like political commentators were crashing around their bedroom at night trying to get to the bathroom. Not really recognizing what they were bumping into. For example many focused too much on Trump without realizing he just represented the yearning of a huge number of Americans. Many others viewed him as a uniquely American problem, and failed to see that there has been an absolute plague of Authoritarian governments in the world recently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/we-are-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/we-are-one/</guid>
      <description>Everything is God (the Universe) and God (the Universe) is love&amp;quot;
Does this ring true to you? It is the core belief of the various New Thought religions such as the Centers for Spiritual Living (CSL) . The truth of these words live in my full body not just my head. Back when I was still an atheist I spent many Sundays in CSL church standing and crying as I awoke to this deeper truth.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
