<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Red Shadow Work on </title>
    <link>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Red Shadow Work on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nonviolence</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/non-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/non-violence/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t oppose all wars. …What I am opposed to is a dumb war. What I am opposed to is a rash war. Barack Obama’s first anti-war speech
Sometimes we have to fight back. As I write this bombs are still falling on Ukraine. A mother and her child are killed trying to get into a shelter. Beloved pets left to wander the rubble. This has been going on for far, far too long.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truth</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/truth/</guid>
      <description>Let me acknowledge yet again that sometimes we have very good reasons for hiding the truth from ourself or others. But the problem with that is until we find our way to our truth we can’t effectively deal with our problems. Let me use my acne cysts as an example again. My mother told me over and over that I was very attractive. But when my sister was having a fancy wedding, I got a call from both my mom and my sister to make sure that I would be OK with getting serious makeup work done before the wedding pictures were taken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mindfulness</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/mindfulness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/mindfulness/</guid>
      <description>A woman I was exploring dating with asked me what my accomplishments were. I struggled to come up with an answer. I love computer programming and have done some good work on some fun projects, but I don’t really hold on to any part of my career as an “accomplishment”. The woman abruptly cut off contact after that — she needed someone who has accomplished something in life. That stung but it was fine, I already had recognized that she had way too much ego attachment for a relationship to work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mind/Body</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/mind-body/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/mind-body/</guid>
      <description>One of my favorite memories is sitting next to a man at a BDSM “munch” (monthly gathering) and talking about his corset pictures. We were conspiring to attract one of the female doms that he wanted to do a play session with. I loved the frank honesty of the munch group — they were clear what worked for them sexually and were honest about it. I also loved how it was so clear that whether you liked to dominate or submit was not tied to gender.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/change/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/change/</guid>
      <description>Change is messy and scary so we resist with all our might. But it is what we have to do. We can stay blocked for years and years, but organicity is always striving towards health and eventually something has to give. Let me give an example.
I was in Guatemala with my (now) ex-wife and daughter for a month, and while we there my testosterone prescription ran out. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get a refill but it turns out that Guatemalan pharmacies will sell you pretty much anything they have without the need for a prescription.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organicity</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/organicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/organicity/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/unity/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/love/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/love/</guid>
      <description>“People will only protect what they love.” Jacques Cousteau</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
