<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Red Shadow Work</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/red_work/index.html</link>
    <description>At the very start of my sophomore year in high school I woke up from a really clear dream. I don’t usually remember my dreams and it is even more rare that they have a clear message from them so this felt like a big deal. The dream was telling me to join the football team. I hadn’t played football my freshman year and I had already missed out on the summer training session so they were reluctant to even let me on. I was allowed to practice, but not even given full equipment. Everyone was quite skeptical of me, heck, I was skeptical of me. As I’ve said I don’t exactly identify as a typical male. But I just knew that I needed to be there.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/waking-up/red_work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nonviolence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/red_work/non-violence/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/red_work/non-violence/index.html</guid>
      <description>I don’t oppose all wars. …What I am opposed to is a dumb war. What I am opposed to is a rash war. Barack Obama’s first anti-war speech&#xA;Sometimes we have to fight back. As I write this bombs are still falling on Ukraine. A mother and her child are killed trying to get into a shelter. Beloved pets left to wander the rubble. This has been going on for far, far too long. So many war crimes committed by Russia. Millions of people have fled the country, and the people still there have to deal with senseless death falling from the sky. We cheer as we watch the Ukrainians bravely fight back against what at first seemed hopeless odds. Sometimes there is no choice but to meet violence with violence. In World War II most of the world had collapsed into authoritarian Red. The only thing that saved us was armed conflict; nothing else would do against Hitler and Tojo. Unbelievable numbers of people died in the resistance but it was sadly necessary. The people we were fighting, the Germans, the Japanese, believed that they too were doing the hard but necessary thing. They also were dying for something they believed in. When it gets this bad we have no choice but to fight. But our goal is to create a world where it doesn’t get that bad. How do we do that? Again, we need systems thinking. We need to go deep enough to really get to the root of the problem. And as always that leads us right back to ourselves.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Truth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/red_work/truth/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/red_work/truth/index.html</guid>
      <description>Let’s go back to accountability. I touched upon it in Beige, and Purple but it is here in Red where it gets real. Let’s approach accountability this time with a warrior’s mindset. When a warrior wants to get something done, they don’t get bogged down in all the excuses of why its other peoples fault. A warrior knows how to step into their power.&#xA;But most of us, most of the time are not in our power. Instead we are giving it away to someone else. Personally, I realized that it was not a question of if I was giving my power away but to who in that moment. I was always giving away my power — my boss, my partner, my family — I was always giving it away. This is the Victim mindset. And what the Victim likes to do best is to recruit Rescuers to rally against the Perpetrator.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mindfulness</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/red_work/mindfulness/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/red_work/mindfulness/index.html</guid>
      <description>To get to where we need to go I’m asking you to step into the more difficult truths. Again, if this all gets too much, please, please take care of yourself. We usually lie to ourselves for a very good reason. And that is OK. Truly. And yet, as much as you safely can, please recognize that we all are holding back from any number of truths. This work takes patience and gentleness. The more we try to force it the harder we fight. The trick is to just stay curious and mindful. Huh. What was that right now? Notice how I quickly swept that thought away? Hmm. What is going on here? I sense there is something more here. Do you see how this works? The very first thing is to not beat yourself up around the lying. We have very good reasons to lie to ourselves — a part of us is trying to protect ourselves from a lot of pain. And going into this deeper truth can be very hard and painful. So why on earth would you do this work? Because it is a path to joy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mind/Body</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/red_work/mind-body/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/red_work/mind-body/index.html</guid>
      <description>When I finally let it, my body guided me to some “dark” truths about myself. For example, it turns out I love to dominate. I secretly love to force my way on people. And how do I know this? Because of how delightful it feels. It showed up in football, and when I let it, it shows up when I have sex. Initially I was so horrified about this that I carefully kept even a hint of this from myself. But it is there alright. In BDSM there is something called “consensual non-consent”. It means that two parties agree to one forcing themselves upon the other. It is important to note that both parties want this and there are some safety precautions like setting up a “safe” word. But the reality is that we are setting up a rape scene. And I am the rapist. It doesn’t get much darker than that. And yet it lights up both of us. There is something electric about this power dynamic. Our bodies are guiding the way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Change</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/red_work/change/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/red_work/change/index.html</guid>
      <description>Change is messy and scary so we resist with all our might. But it is what we have to do. We can stay blocked for years and years, but organicity is always striving towards health and eventually something has to give. Let me give an example.&#xA;I was in Guatemala with my (now) ex-wife and daughter for a month, and while we there my testosterone prescription ran out. I couldn’t get a refill but it turns out that Guatemalan pharmacies will sell you pretty much anything they have without the need for a prescription. And they had this high quality testosterone made in Switzerland. Apparently you did just one injection and then you were good for a couple of months. That sounded pretty good – the daily cream application was a hassle. So I had my ex inject me one night and we went to bed. I woke up in the early hours of the morning and I knew everything had to change. Everything. My ex suffered from extreme anxiety and she constantly was hit with crippling migraines that would keep her in bed for days. She felt a desperate need to control the world because it felt like her very survival was at stake. We had fallen into a bad pattern where she pretty much controlled everything about our lives. I went along with all this because I loved her and wanted to help, but it didn’t work for either of us.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organicity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/red_work/organicity/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/red_work/organicity/index.html</guid>
      <description>Again, organicity simply asks the question, “What wants to happen next?” and then the follow up question, “What is blocking that?”. Let me give you an example.&#xA;I once did a series of three all day San Pedro (a type of cactus) medicine ceremonies. San Pedro is a very gentle hallucinogen that lasts for a very long time and you are fairly lucid most of that time. I did it with the same group each time, and the ceremonies were spaced roughly a month apart with a group meeting before and after each ceremony. We were asked to bring something to place on the altar for each session, something that would help guide us in out intentions. I didn’t know exactly why but something was telling me to bring this dragon that I had on my altar. I didn’t even know why I felt called to even put the dragon on my altar in the first place, but I have learned to follow my intuitions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/red_work/unity/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/red_work/unity/index.html</guid>
      <description>The Unity principle at Red brings us back to knowing that we all have the rapist and murderer inside of us. We all embody both Trump and Hitler. They are not separate from us. Do you recoil from that? I know I certainly do. That can’t be true! But it is.&#xA;Time for confession. During this latest pandemic surge I did the math for how many amongst the vaccine refusers were Trump supporters. I wanted to see if the number of their deaths would change anything politically. The super dark side of this? I was hoping it would. Do you know who else had this kind of mindset? Hitler. If only we got rid of “those” people things would be so much better. Again we have to step back from “good” and “evil”. When we point our finger at “those” people there are three fingers pointing right back at us.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Love</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/red_work/love/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/red_work/love/index.html</guid>
      <description>“People will only protect what they love.” Jacques Cousteau&#xA;When I found out my beloved partner was maybe falling in love with another man I went through wild, manic swings. One moment I was pouring all my heart and soul into figuring out a way to fix it. Then I would get so angry I would clench my fists and shout. Then I got so sad that I couldn’t sleep. I went so many nights without sleep that when I shut my eyes I had vivid hallucinations. I’ve aways thought “heart breaking” was a poetic term. Nope, turns out it is a very real, physical thing. Where my love for her used to be was now a million scattered pieces of heart. Maybe I don’t love her anymore I told myself. Then I really let myself explore leaving her, and the pain got so great I didn’t know if I could bear it. We had created such a great life together, and created so many great memories. Sure I could probably find someone else, but I really don’t want to. To make it even more crazy making she was walking the El Camino in Spain for 8 weeks while this all blew up so we were physically distant. I sent her an angry email and was quite surprised that that didn’t immediately have her come running to me. Instead she told me she needed to process and pulled back from communicating with me except for brief superficial texts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Saves the World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/red_work/red-saves-the-world/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/red_work/red-saves-the-world/index.html</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Homework</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/red_work/homework/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/red_work/homework/index.html</guid>
      <description>Red is definitely, by far, my weakest stage. I’m still trying to figure out what works best for me to strengthen this. I would very much appreciate suggestions on what to add here. What has worked for you?&#xA;That said, I do know some things to strengthen Red.&#xA;Face your fears Even to this day sometimes when I come up to the edge of a cliff, I pull back because I have this weird fear that I will impulsively jump off. What was the best way to deal with this fear of heights? Paragliding. There is something about pulling up a paraglider off the ground, turning around and running off a cliff that is amazing. Every time I do it I’m terrified and yet I love soaring free in the air. And the sense of mastery and adventure! I tend to think of warriors as doing the grim difficult thing. And that is definitely a part of it, but oh the joy! The sense of stepping beyond your bounds. The wonder of doing something scary and dangerous but surviving anyways.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>