<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Red Shadow Work on </title>
    <link>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Red Shadow Work on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nonviolence</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/non-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/non-violence/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t oppose all wars. …What I am opposed to is a dumb war. What I am opposed to is a rash war. Barack Obama’s first anti-war speech
Sometimes we have to fight back. As I write this bombs are still falling on Ukraine. A mother and her child are killed trying to get into a shelter. Beloved pets left to wander the rubble. This has been going on for far, far too long.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truth</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/truth/</guid>
      <description>Let’s go back to accountability. I touched upon it in Beige, and Purple but it is here in Red where it gets real. Let’s approach accountability this time with a warrior’s mindset. When a warrior wants to get something done, they don’t get bogged down in all the excuses of why its other peoples fault. A warrior knows how to step into their power.
But most of us, most of the time are not in our power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mindfulness</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/mindfulness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/mindfulness/</guid>
      <description>To get to where we need to go I’m asking you to step into the more difficult truths. Again, if this all gets too much, please, please take care of yourself. We usually lie to ourselves for a very good reason. And that is OK. Truly. And yet, as much as you safely can, please recognize that we all are holding back from any number of truths. This work takes patience and gentleness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mind/Body</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/mind-body/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/mind-body/</guid>
      <description>When I finally let it, my body guided me to some “dark” truths about myself. For example, it turns out I love to dominate. I secretly love to force my way on people. And how do I know this? Because of how delightful it feels. It showed up in football, and when I let it, it shows up when I have sex. Initially I was so horrified about this that I carefully kept even a hint of this from myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/change/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/change/</guid>
      <description>Change is messy and scary so we resist with all our might. But it is what we have to do. We can stay blocked for years and years, but organicity is always striving towards health and eventually something has to give. Let me give an example.
I was in Guatemala with my (now) ex-wife and daughter for a month, and while we there my testosterone prescription ran out. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get a refill but it turns out that Guatemalan pharmacies will sell you pretty much anything they have without the need for a prescription.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organicity</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/organicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/organicity/</guid>
      <description>Again, organicity simply asks the question, “What wants to happen next?” and then the follow up question, “What is blocking that?”. Let me give you an example.
I once did a series of three all day San Pedro (a type of cactus) medicine ceremonies. San Pedro is a very gentle hallucinogen that lasts for a very long time and you are fairly lucid most of that time. I did it with the same group each time, and the ceremonies were spaced roughly a month apart with a group meeting before and after each ceremony.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/unity/</guid>
      <description>The Unity principle at Red brings us back to knowing that we all have the rapist and murderer inside of us. We all embody both Trump and Hitler. They are not separate from us. Do you recoil from that? I know I certainly do. That can’t be true! But it is.
Time for confession. During this latest pandemic surge I did the math for how many amongst the vaccine refusers were Trump supporters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/love/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/love/</guid>
      <description>“People will only protect what they love.” Jacques Cousteau
When I found out my beloved partner was maybe falling in love with another man I went through wild, manic swings. One moment I was pouring all my heart and soul into figuring out a way to fix it. Then I would get so angry I would clench my fists and shout. Then I got so sad that I couldn’t sleep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Saves the World</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/red-saves-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/red-saves-the-world/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homework</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/homework/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/red_work/homework/</guid>
      <description>Red is definitely, by far, my weakest stage. I’m still trying to figure out what works best for me to strengthen this. I would very much appreciate suggestions on what to add here. What has worked for you?
That said, I do know some things to strengthen Red.
Face your fears Even to this day sometimes when I come up to the edge of a cliff, I pull back because I have this weird fear that I will impulsively jump off.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
