<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Purple wisdom on </title>
    <link>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Purple wisdom on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 05:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nonviolence</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/non-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/non-violence/</guid>
      <description>There sometimes is tremendous temptation to help people along by getting a little tough with them for their own good. Maybe hold them accountable for what they said they would do but didn&amp;rsquo;t. Maybe point them in the direction they need to go and push them a little. Some personal growth workshops take this approach and for a brief time people will have remarkable results. But the results don&amp;rsquo;t last. This is not the path to healing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truth</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/truth/</guid>
      <description>In Beige we look inside ourselves for our truth. In Purple we start to let the truth of others in as well. Just about all of my major work has happened in a group process like HAI. And HAI workshops revolve around group shares. People stand up in front of the group (usually stark naked) and are lovingly encouraged to share from the most vulnerable, authentic place they can find within themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mindfulness</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/mindfulness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/mindfulness/</guid>
      <description>There is a lot of truly great writing about mindfulness. For example, Mark Manson has an excellent articlehere. I also love what he has to say about meditation which is a practical tool to help us cultivate mindfulness. In his vivid way he describes all the amazing benefits both health-wise and mental of meditation. But we tend to think of meditation as the only way to cultivate mindfulness. It is not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mind/Body</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/mind-body/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/mind-body/</guid>
      <description>I talked about taking care our bodies. Let’s now go deeper and talk about what happens when we have trauma. When we suffer a traumatic event we store that trauma somewhere in our body. When Bessel van der Kolk, author of The Body Keeps the Score, first started out as a psychiatrist his profession didn&amp;rsquo;t have much to offer traumatized people. They didn&amp;rsquo;t even really recognize PTSD as a thing. That has changed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organicity</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/organicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/organicity/</guid>
      <description>I’m afraid that by just reading this site you will get the impression that this personal growth stuff is all very serious, hard work that involves a lot of suffering. It can be that way, but it doesn’t have to be. If you find the right healing group this work actually becomes tremendous fun. Yes it is still very challenging, but it just feels right. You are not alone. Others are doing similar work as you and you are supporting each other every step of the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/change/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/change/</guid>
      <description>I recently watch a movie called Manchester by the Sea. The acting is amazing and the overall quality is very high. But I don’t recommend the movie. At all. I think the movie in its confusion and ignorance promotes a very dangerous story. It portrays deeply, deeply traumatized people stumbling around causing harm to themselves and others without any recognition that it doesn’t have to be like that. It is caught in the harmful story that there is nothing you can do to heal trauma.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/unity/</guid>
      <description>Again, Americans have a huge blindspot about groups. We just don’t seem to get that not everything is just about me. When I try to explain this to people I sometimes get frustrated until I remember it took me an entire year of living in Japan and married to a Japanese woman to get this — no wonder people don’t get it. It is like trying to talk to fish about the water they are swimming in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loving Presence</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/love/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/love/</guid>
      <description>In Beige I introduced the loving kindness Metta practice. I didn’t really go into the details of how to do it because first you need to learn how to love yourself. And if you struggle with that then first focus on the people (or animals at least?) in your life that you love and then circle back to yourself. But now let’s go one step further. There is already a lot written on this topic and I don’t really want to duplicate that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When We Clean Up We Save The World</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/cleaningupstwi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/cleaningupstwi/</guid>
      <description>Cleaning Up sets the foundation for everything else. Unless we have dealt with our traumas and pain we will just keep on broadcasting them out into the world. Quite often we pass them on to our children. This must stop.
No more Trauma So what is our vision? No more trauma. Period. Let’s first start with the children. Let this be the very last generation of traumatized children.
No more traumatized children We need to spend a completely unreasonable amount of time, money, and energy on our children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homework</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/homework/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/homework/</guid>
      <description>In the Beige homework section I suggested you start with yourself. In Purple my suggestion is to now start doing this work with others. There is tremendous healing power in groups.
Trauma Test This is the big one. You almost certainly know on some level if you have had major trauma. What was your childhood like? Were you beaten or abused or maybe simply neglected? Those all can cause deep trauma.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/untitled/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/untitled/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
