<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Purple wisdom</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/index.html</link>
    <description>Coming home on the bus from the “Wall” workshop I thought we were all done with our growth work; time to go back to the normal world. But not everyone felt like that apparently. A middle aged woman on the bus was still working through something. She asked one of the young men to role play her estranged son. They did a perfect job. I sat and watched from one seat back with folded arms feeling very superior to the woman. It was so obvious she was stuck in not forgiving herself. Then like a thunderbolt it hit me that she was doing my work. I also was not forgiving myself and it was causing me a lot of pain.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 05:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nonviolence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/non-violence/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/non-violence/index.html</guid>
      <description>There sometimes is tremendous temptation to help people along by getting a little tough with them for their own good. Maybe hold them accountable for what they said they would do but didn’t. Maybe point them in the direction they need to go and push them a little. Some personal growth workshops take this approach and for a brief time people will have remarkable results. But the results don’t last. This is not the path to healing. Not really. And sometimes when we push too hard we hurt people. I had a good friend badly wounded by the Landmark Forum. They pushed her so hard she had a nervous breakdown.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Truth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/truth/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/truth/index.html</guid>
      <description>In Beige we look inside ourselves for our truth. In Purple we start to let the truth of others in as well. Just about all of my major work has happened in a group process like HAI. And HAI workshops revolve around group shares. People stand up in front of the group (usually stark naked) and are lovingly encouraged to share from the most vulnerable, authentic place they can find within themselves. Quite often people are inspired to stand up after having a breakthrough during one of the exercises. Or maybe they are moved to share their most painful secret. There is something incredibly beautiful about sharing your deepest, naked Truth in front of a circle of sacred witnesses. A circle that holds all of you in love. This group support helped me to get to my deeper places. Helped me get clearer about what was really going on for me. When I stood up sometimes it was like something was speaking through me. Afterwards I would sit down and run through what I just said because it was what I most needed to hear.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mindfulness</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/mindfulness/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/mindfulness/index.html</guid>
      <description>There is a lot of truly great writing about mindfulness. For example, Mark Manson has an excellent articlehere. I also love what he has to say about meditation which is a practical tool to help us cultivate mindfulness. In his vivid way he describes all the amazing benefits both health-wise and mental of meditation. But we tend to think of meditation as the only way to cultivate mindfulness. It is not. Meditation is not the answer to all our problems. Don’t get me wrong – I love meditation. I meditate daily in front of my beloved altar and it has helped me a lot. And recently it is the only thing that helped when I was in a relationship crisis. So I know how powerful it is. But I have seen too many people take up meditation as The One True Way, and not realizing it is not the answer all by itself. It needs to be combined with other ways.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mind/Body</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/mind-body/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/mind-body/index.html</guid>
      <description>I talked about taking care our bodies. Let’s now go deeper and talk about what happens when we have trauma. When we suffer a traumatic event we store that trauma somewhere in our body. When Bessel van der Kolk, author of The Body Keeps the Score, first started out as a psychiatrist his profession didn’t have much to offer traumatized people. They didn’t even really recognize PTSD as a thing. That has changed. In the second half of his book he describes the many, many different, promising therapy options for trauma we have now. This is huge. Maybe for the first time since the start of Red empire we have the chance to finally stop the cycle of one generation passing it’s trauma on to the next. And as different as all these therapy options are they do share two thing – first, they help people connect their bodies back into the world, and second, they do it with the help of others.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organicity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/organicity/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/organicity/index.html</guid>
      <description>I’m afraid that by just reading this site you will get the impression that this personal growth stuff is all very serious, hard work that involves a lot of suffering. It can be that way, but it doesn’t have to be. If you find the right healing group this work actually becomes tremendous fun. Yes it is still very challenging, but it just feels right. You are not alone. Others are doing similar work as you and you are supporting each other every step of the way. There is a knowing within and a sense of flowing in the right direction. That is the heart of organicity. We learn to trust that our organism is always striving towards health. Always. We intuitively know what we need, we just need to get out of our own way to let it happen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Change</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/change/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/change/index.html</guid>
      <description>I recently watch a movie called Manchester by the Sea. The acting is amazing and the overall quality is very high. But I don’t recommend the movie. At all. I think the movie in its confusion and ignorance promotes a very dangerous story. It portrays deeply, deeply traumatized people stumbling around causing harm to themselves and others without any recognition that it doesn’t have to be like that. It is caught in the harmful story that there is nothing you can do to heal trauma. It is as if the actors portrayed burn victims just making do with their festering wounds and just accepting that it had to be that way. Hospitals?!? Pffft. As if. Real people just suffer. This is dangerous, ignorant nonsense. But it is understandable. Up to now that is all we knew. We have only recently rediscovered what Purple knew all along — we can heal trauma. But we have to first accept that this is even possible.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/unity/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/unity/index.html</guid>
      <description>Again, Americans have a huge blindspot about groups. We just don’t seem to get that not everything is just about me. When I try to explain this to people I sometimes get frustrated until I remember it took me an entire year of living in Japan and married to a Japanese woman to get this — no wonder most Americans don’t get it. It is like trying to talk to fish about the water they are swimming in. Water? What are you talking about? And yet we are all floating around in this trance of the rugged individualist. I see it in all sorts of places. It is what makes driving so scary sometimes. When I drive in California I have to remember that most of the other drivers seem to believe they are in a driving game and consider all the other drivers to be just npc’s — not real. To stay safe I have to just assume people will act in selfish, random ways and not get too flustered by the occasional road rage incident. Again, I’m not real to them. And they certainly don’t have any conception of being part of a greater whole — at least not while they are driving. This attitude shows up in how we do our healing work as well.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Loving Presence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/love/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/love/index.html</guid>
      <description>In Beige I introduced the loving kindness Metta practice. I didn’t really go into the details of how to do it because first you need to learn how to love yourself. And if you struggle with that then first focus on the people (or animals at least?) in your life that you love and then circle back to yourself. But now let’s go one step further. There is already a lot written on this topic and I don’t really want to duplicate that. So before we get into it please quickly scan through this website:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When We Clean Up We Save The World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/cleaningupstwi/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/cleaningupstwi/index.html</guid>
      <description>Cleaning Up sets the foundation for everything else. Unless we have dealt with our traumas and pain we will just keep on broadcasting them out into the world. Quite often we pass them on to our children. This must stop.&#xA;No more Trauma So what is our vision? No more trauma. Period. Let’s first start with the children. Let this be the very last generation of traumatized children.&#xA;No more traumatized children We need to spend a completely unreasonable amount of time, money, and energy on our children. This first of all. I was quite serious when I said that preschool and kindergarten teachers must lead the revolution. They are with our children at those incredibly tender years when all those childhood traumas happen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Homework</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/homework/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/purple-wisdom-work/homework/index.html</guid>
      <description>In the Beige homework section I suggested you start with yourself. In Purple my suggestion is to now start doing this work with others. There is tremendous healing power in groups.&#xA;Trauma Test This is the big one. You almost certainly know on some level if you have had major trauma. What was your childhood like? Were you beaten or abused or maybe simply neglected? Those all can cause deep trauma. Have you been in a situation where people got killed and your own life was at risk? Have you been placed in an impossible situation where you had to do something unspeakable? Or maybe simply you grew up sensitive in a very harsh world. That all alone can cause deep trauma. Please don’t dismiss your trauma as less than others. It all hurts.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>