<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cleaning Up on Save The World</title>
    <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cleaning Up on Save The World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 05:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/why/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/why/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s start with Aaron Stark&amp;rsquo;s story.
  Do you see why it has to start here? There are so many, many children that could tell similar stories. This has to stop! These kids need our love and support. But instead just like in Aaron&amp;rsquo;s story the social worker buys into his mom&amp;rsquo;s well practiced lies and steps back and does nothing. Making the situation even worse than it was before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hakomi Principles</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/hakomi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/hakomi/</guid>
      <description>Non violence Mindfulness Mind/Body Truth Change Organicity Unity Loving Presence  Hakomi therapists are working to save the world. But here I am going to focus mainly on its principles. These principles are a foundation we can build on. They can be our North star to help guide us when we get lost. These principles work together. All of them are necessary. If a Hakomi session didn&amp;rsquo;t go well, students are taught to look to the principles to see what was missing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nonviolence</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/non-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/non-violence/</guid>
      <description>As I write this bombs are falling on Ukranian homes. Families are huddled in subways just trying to survive, and a million people have fled the country. We cheer as we watch the Ukranians bravely fight back against what seem hopeless odds. Sometimes there is no choice but to meet violence with violence. In World War II most of the world had collapsed into authoritarian Red. The only thing that saved us was armed conflict; nothing else would do against Hitler and Tojo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mindfulness</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/mindfulness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/mindfulness/</guid>
      <description>Healing revolves around mindfulness. We encourage people to stop, take a breath, and really pay attention to what is going on with themselves. As people start to realize what a truly safe space they are in they feel safer to start exploring some of their scarier places. We gently remind them to close their eyes and really get in touch with how they are feeling. This is a core method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mind/Body</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/mind-body/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/mind-body/</guid>
      <description>What happens in our body affects our Mind. What happens in our Mind affects our body. It is all one. HAI works very hard to get people deeply connected to their bodies. It is one of the major reasons why HAI invites people to take their clothes off. It is why we spend so much time stroking each other. Our culture has profound dysfunction around sexuality. Many of us have had wounding around our bodies or sex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nature</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/nature/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/nature/</guid>
      <description> Nature  We are zoo animals The book &amp;ldquo;Wild&amp;rdquo; Forest therapy    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/change/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/change/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treatment</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/treatment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/treatment/</guid>
      <description>Outline  Treatments that I personally know work  Backpacking  Wild (?)   Thread story (about support for a junior high student) Mdma HAI   Healing practices  RAIN Trust organicity Trauma work    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truth</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/truth/</guid>
      <description>Hakomi teaches that we all have core beliefs that are driving us without us consciously realizing it. You first need to build a loving bubble with your client, and let them really get how safe they are with you. Let them see that you will respect and honor all parts of them. Then you encourage them to go deeper. We take them to a non ordinary state of consciousness where they can get to the core of themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organicity</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/organicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/organicity/</guid>
      <description>Living organisms are always striving to grow and heal. Always. There might be something blocking it, but that is where things naturally want to go. We need to understand that our job is to step back and let it happen. We create a loving, safe learning environment and then have faith that people will find their own way to the healing they need. This is somewhat humbling. We are not the healers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/unity/</guid>
      <description>There is a certain connection magic that always comes up for a group that goes through something intense together. People connect and become one. It is part of being human. We are a deeply social animal and we are meant to form groups both large and small. We even have mirror neurons dedicated to this task. If someone is grieving I grieve too. If someone is in pain I hurt also.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loving Presence</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/love/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/love/</guid>
      <description>This is the base. Everything has to be built on top of this. In Hakomi we were taught to build a loving &amp;ldquo;bubble&amp;rdquo; between ourselves and our client. In HAI it comes from the deep love from the facilitators and the team. They are all there because they are deeply committed to love and together they create the same &amp;ldquo;bubble&amp;rdquo; but for an entire room. The very first thing the facilitators do is to model loving, tender connection with each other.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
