<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Beige healing on Save The World</title>
    <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/beige-healing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Beige healing on Save The World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 05:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/beige-healing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nonviolence</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/beige-healing/non-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/beige-healing/non-violence/</guid>
      <description>Huge acne cysts sprang up on my face at the end of my sophomore year in high school. They swelled so big that my skin was pulled painfully tight and made it hard to smile. They were almost as big as ping pong balls &amp;ndash; I am not exaggerating. And when they finally, finally popped tthey left very big, deep, pitted scars. And they kept on coming. I went from one of the cuter boys to one of the ugliest just like that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truth</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/beige-healing/truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/beige-healing/truth/</guid>
      <description>It turns out that I could have avoided those horrible acne cysts simply by changing my diet. My hometown happened to have one of the very few dermatologists in the country who understood that. If I had gone to him right away I would have been spared most of my trauma. The problem was that I have a kind of allergy to milk fat. And I was consuming a lot of it — I was drinking close to a gallon of milk a day (growing teenage boy) not to mention all the pizza and ice cream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mindfulness</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/beige-healing/mindfulness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/beige-healing/mindfulness/</guid>
      <description>When I was in college I went to the Zen center at Green Gulch north of San Francisco to meditate for a week. I knew how rigorous it was going to be so I diligently practiced zazen until I could sit for almost an hour in perfect stillness. I was quite proud of my ability. At the zen center we sat so quietly that even if someone swallowed you could hear it so I tried to not even do that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mind/Body</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/beige-healing/mind-body/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/beige-healing/mind-body/</guid>
      <description>I talk about how small our world becomes when our health fails because I have lived through that. In December 2013, I had just gotten laid off and suddenly I was sick all of the time. I would be OK for a couple of days or even a week but then another cold or flu would hit and I would go back to being sick. On top of that I would get bouts of vertigo and have to reach out to something to keep from falling over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organicity</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/beige-healing/organicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/beige-healing/organicity/</guid>
      <description>I don’t think people are seeking the meaning of life as much as they are seeking the experience of being alive.” Joseph Campbell
 &amp;ldquo;Organicity&amp;rdquo; is an unfamiliar, awkward word, and I have to confess I initially resisted it. My partner especially dislikes it but try as we might we can&amp;rsquo;t come up with an alternative. We really do need a new word here. Ignore what the dictionary might say, in this sense the word combines &amp;ldquo;organism&amp;rdquo; with &amp;ldquo;icity&amp;rdquo; to mean the nature of an organism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/beige-healing/change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/beige-healing/change/</guid>
      <description>While I was writing this section, I had a urinary infection that made it painful to pee. I kept on ignoring and ignoring it for two weeks. Finally it got so painful even I could no longer ignore it so I went into urgent care and got a prescription that cleared me up pretty much in one day. Why did I wait so long? Now with the infection gone I realize how much it was weighing on me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loving Presence</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/beige-healing/love/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/beige-healing/love/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;All human behavior is either an act of love or a cry for love&amp;rdquo; Stan Dale
  “The hardest to learn was the least complicated” Indigo Girls
 Let&amp;rsquo;s go back to Aaron Stark&amp;rsquo;s story about how he almost became a school shooter. What saved him? Simply a friend&amp;rsquo;s undemanding love. The friend wasn&amp;rsquo;t trying to fix him, he just wanted to spend time with him. Even though Aaron had lied to him and stolen from him, his friend was still there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/beige-healing/unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/beige-healing/unity/</guid>
      <description>There is a certain connection magic that always comes up for a group that goes through something intense together. People connect and become one. It is part of being human. We are a deeply social animal and we are meant to form groups both large and small. We even have mirror neurons dedicated to this task.
If someone is grieving I grieve too. If someone is in pain I hurt also.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Homework”</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/beige-healing/homework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/cleaning-up/beige-healing/homework/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
