<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Beige healing on Save The World</title>
    <link>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/beige-healing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Beige healing on Save The World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 05:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/beige-healing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nonviolence</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/beige-healing/non-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/beige-healing/non-violence/</guid>
      <description>Huge acne cysts sprang up on my face at the end of my sophomore year in high school. They swelled so big that my skin was pulled painfully tight and made it hard to smile. They were almost as big as ping pong balls &amp;ndash; I am not exaggerating. And when finally, finally I forced them to pop they left very big, deep, pitted scars. And they kept on coming. I went from one of the cuter boys to one of the ugliest just like that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truth</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/beige-healing/truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/beige-healing/truth/</guid>
      <description>It turns out that I could have avoided those horrible acne cysts simply by changing my diet. My hometown happened to have one of the very few dermatologists in the country who understood that. If I had gone to him right away I would have been spared most of my trauma. The problem was that I have a particular kind of allergy to milk fat. And I was consuming a lot of it — I was drinking close to a gallon of milk a day (growing teenage boy) not to mention all the pizza and ice cream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mindfulness</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/beige-healing/mindfulness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/beige-healing/mindfulness/</guid>
      <description>When I was in college I went to the Zen center at Green Gulch north of San Francisco to meditate for a week. I knew how rigorous it was going to be so I diligently practiced zazen until I could sit for almost an hour in perfect stillness. I was quite proud of my ability. At the zen center we sat so quietly that even if someone swallowed you could hear it so I tried to not even do that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mind/Body</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/beige-healing/mind-body/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/beige-healing/mind-body/</guid>
      <description>We tend to hold our bodies and minds as separate things. They are not. And if our body is suffering we are not up for anything other than simple survival; we certainly are not up for saving the world. I know this personally. In December 2013, I had just gotten laid off and suddenly I was sick all of the time. I would be OK for a couple of days or even a week but then another cold or flu would hit and I would go back to being sick.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organicity</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/beige-healing/organicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/beige-healing/organicity/</guid>
      <description>I don’t think people are seeking the meaning of life as much as they are seeking the experience of being alive.” Joseph Campbell
&amp;ldquo;Organicity&amp;rdquo; is an unfamiliar, awkward word, and I have to confess I initially resisted it. My partner also initially really disliked it but try as we might we couldn’t come up with an alternative. Surprisingly this eventually became her favorite principal (possibly because it is the only one she remembers).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/beige-healing/change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/beige-healing/change/</guid>
      <description>While I was writing this section, I had a urinary infection that made it painful to pee. I kept on ignoring and ignoring it for two weeks. Finally it got so painful even I could no longer ignore it so I went into urgent care and got a prescription that cleared me up pretty much in one day. Why did I wait so long? Now with the infection gone I realize how much it was weighing on me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/beige-healing/unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/beige-healing/unity/</guid>
      <description>We can have our ecstatic moments, but what really matters is what we bring back to our daily life. When starting a Medicine journey, quite often we struggle to surrender to the medicine, but once we do we almost always eventually end up in a beautiful spot. Maybe we wrap our arms around an angel and blast to another planet, or maybe we die and once we get past that horror find ourself in a world of peaceful joy where our painful body no longer troubles us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loving Presence</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/beige-healing/love/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/beige-healing/love/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;All human behavior is either an act of love or a cry for love&amp;rdquo; Stan Dale
“The hardest to learn was the least complicated” Indigo Girls
Let&amp;rsquo;s go back to Aaron Stark&amp;rsquo;s story about how he almost became a school shooter. What saved him? A friend&amp;rsquo;s undemanding love. The friend wasn&amp;rsquo;t trying to fix him, he just wanted to spend time with him. Even though Aaron had lied to him and stolen from him, his friend was still there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcoming Beige</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/beige-healing/welcoming-beige/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/beige-healing/welcoming-beige/</guid>
      <description>Ok, so now that we have gone through the different aspects of Beige, how do we welcome more of it into the world. What are the practical things we can do? Again this is kind of like an affirmative prayer — the clearer we can visualize this the more likely it is to happen.
Advocates Like many kids my daughter was totally thrown off by the pandemic. She was already struggling with school and now she had to do school online?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homework</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/beige-healing/homework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/cleaning-up/beige-healing/homework/</guid>
      <description>For each of the stages I am going to ask you to test yourself and then I will suggest homework. For Beige I am going to mainly suggest reading books. If that sounds like too much please consider using audio books. The beauty of audio books is that you can listen to them for 15 minutes in the car while driving somewhere. I got through a couple of the suggested books below that way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
