<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Beige healing</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/beige-healing/index.html</link>
    <description>Let’s start with Aaron Stark’s story. Please watch it.&#xA;Do you see why it has to start here? There are so many, many children that could tell similar stories. This has to stop! These kids need our love and support. But instead just like in Aaron’s story the social worker buys into his mom’s well practiced lies and steps back and does nothing. Making the situation even worse than it was before. It is almost as if children are their parent’s property to do with as they see fit. That is so obviously wrong, and yet I think it is our reality. We, just like that social worker, want to believe the comforting lie that a child is always better off with their mother. But unfortunately quite often that mother was also raised by deeply traumatized parents and so she too is acting out of pain. Not truly wanting to but nevertheless deeply wounding her child. One generation passing its trauma on to the next generation over and over. We need to stop this cycle.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/beige-healing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nonviolence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/beige-healing/non-violence/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/beige-healing/non-violence/index.html</guid>
      <description>Late in my sophomore year in high school I started getting horrible, huge acne cysts on my face that left permanent, deep scars. I went from one of the cuter boys to one of the uglier just like that. I felt very vulnerable, so I stared into the mirror and told myself over and over “You are ugly”. I was trying to toughen myself . This got all the way in because it was actually done with loving intent – I didn’t want anyone to be able to hurt me. And I was so sure it needed to be done. That it was the only way to protect myself. But it actually destroyed me. I’m not alone. We attack and belittle ourselves. We tell ourselves stories about how unattractive we are, or stupid, or lazy or whatever. And it really hurts. This pain is real and it cripples us. We can’t start to heal until we stop this violence within.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Truth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/beige-healing/truth/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/beige-healing/truth/index.html</guid>
      <description>It turns out that I could have avoided those horrible acne cysts simply by changing my diet. My hometown happened to have one of the very few dermatologists in the country who understood that. If I had gone to him right away I would have been spared most of my trauma. The problem was that I have a particular kind of allergy to milk fat. And I was consuming a lot of it — I was drinking close to a gallon of milk a day (growing teenage boy) not to mention all the pizza and ice cream. If I had given up dairy, the cysts would have stopped just like that.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mindfulness</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/beige-healing/mindfulness/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/beige-healing/mindfulness/index.html</guid>
      <description>When I was in college I went to the Zen center at Green Gulch north of San Francisco to meditate for a week. I knew how rigorous it was going to be so I diligently practiced zazen until I could sit for almost an hour in perfect stillness. I was quite proud of my ability. At the zen center we sat so quietly that even if someone swallowed you could hear it so I tried to not even do that. Then one morning a woman came in who wasn’t as skilled and she shifted and moved around trying to get comfortable quite a bit. What a racket! But after a few days she settled in and got quieter and quieter until one morning at breakfast she remarked, “I heard the ocean this morning!”. A fellow student replied, “It was always there you just needed to get quiet enough to hear it”. And it was true the sound of ocean waves crashing into the beach was always there in the distance but you did have to be very, very still to hear it. In the very same way we need to get still enough to hear what is really going on for us. Usually we are too busy shifting around to get comfortable for us to pay attention.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mind/Body</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/beige-healing/mind-body/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/beige-healing/mind-body/index.html</guid>
      <description>We tend to hold our bodies and minds as separate things. They are not. And if our body is suffering we are not up for anything other than simple survival; we certainly are not up for saving the world.&#xA;Hakomi works with the common traumas people share. One of the most common is insecure attachment. If a child does not feel secure in their relationship to their caregiver they are traumatized. Insecure attachment means a greater chance of mental illness, and successful relationships are much harder. This trauma lives in the body. This is why people go so “crazy” in relationships — their logical mind is no longer in control, they get taken over by this old, deep wound.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organicity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/beige-healing/organicity/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/beige-healing/organicity/index.html</guid>
      <description>I don’t think people are seeking the meaning of life as much as they are seeking the experience of being alive.” Joseph Campbell&#xA;“Organicity” is an unfamiliar, awkward word, and I have to confess I initially resisted it, but we really do need a new word here. Ignore what the dictionary might say, in this sense the word combines “organism” with “icity” to mean the nature of an organism. It focuses us on the living, natural organisms that we all are. We tend to skip right past that, but this principle brings us back over and over to the miracle of life. Brings us back to noticing what our living body is feeling and longing for. Living things are always healing. Always. Isn’t that amazing? A doctor might set a broken bone, but then it is up to the body to do the healing. When a 17 year old girl who I was very close to died of cancer I was devastated. A wise grief counselor told me that we are never the same after our losses, but to know that we are always on a path towards healing. That was comforting to hear. The counselor was reminding me to trust myself. To trust the organism that is myself to guide me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Change</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/beige-healing/change/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/beige-healing/change/index.html</guid>
      <description>While I was writing this section, I had a urinary infection that made it painful to pee. I kept on ignoring and ignoring it for two weeks. Finally it got so painful even I could no longer ignore it so I went into urgent care and got a prescription that cleared me up pretty much in one day. Why did I wait so long? Now with the infection gone I realize how much it was weighing on me. I feel so much better now and have so much more energy! It was blocking me from fully showing up.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/beige-healing/unity/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/beige-healing/unity/index.html</guid>
      <description>We can have our ecstatic moments, but what really matters is what we bring back to our daily life. When starting a Medicine journey, quite often we struggle to surrender to the medicine, but once we do we almost always eventually end up in a beautiful spot. Maybe we wrap our arms around an angel and blast to another planet, or maybe we die and once we get past that horror find ourself in a world of peaceful joy where our painful body no longer troubles us. It can be hard to come back from that. But that is our work — integrating all this new experience. The initial journey is great, but it is in the follow up sessions with the guide where the important work is done. The client now knows what is possible — the work is to fully bring it into themself and live from that place.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Loving Presence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/beige-healing/love/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/beige-healing/love/index.html</guid>
      <description>“All human behavior is either an act of love or a cry for love” Stan Dale (HAI founder)&#xA;“The hardest to learn was the least complicated” Indigo Girls&#xA;Please consider Aaron Stark’s story about how he almost became a school shooter. What saved him? A friend’s undemanding love. The friend wasn’t trying to fix him, he just wanted to spend time with him. Even though Aaron had lied to him and stolen from him, his friend was still there. Love freely given with no expectations. What a beautiful, simple, powerful gift. What would the world look like if more people got the love they needed? Please sit with that thought for a moment. Maybe breathe into it. It really is the core of my plan – my longing is for us to all get back to here. To that place where we feel loved and are willing to take the scary risk of loving others. Loving others is a discipline that can be cultivated and strengthened until it is a way of life. Simple enough to say, but quite hard to do at times. For many of us the hardest to learn was the least complicated. We always have the choice; to love or not, to let love in or not. It is fear and pain that holds us back. That is not where we truly want to be. But to get where we want to go we often need help. We need training.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Homework</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/beige-healing/homework/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/beige-healing/homework/index.html</guid>
      <description>For each of the stages I am going to ask you to test yourself and then I will suggest homework. For Beige I am going to mainly suggest reading books. If that sounds like too much please consider using audio books. The beauty of audio books is that you can listen to them for 15 minutes in the car while driving somewhere. I got through a couple of the suggested books below that way.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>