<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Waking Up on Save The World</title>
    <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/my-waking-up/</link>
    <description>Recent content in My Waking Up on Save The World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 09:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/my-waking-up/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Crisis of Faith</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/my-waking-up/crisis-of-faith/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 09:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/my-waking-up/crisis-of-faith/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I can&amp;rsquo;t quite explain why, but I know what he is saying is not true&amp;rdquo;. We were sitting in a grassy courtyard surrounded by the dark-grey University of Chicago walls. Grey, grey minds always peering down at you was how a friend described the walls, but it was sunny and we were sitting on a park bench looking at the surprisingly pretty, purple-grey pigeons hop around on the grass. We had just gotten out of class, and for some reason this brilliant young woman was taking me into her confidence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truth</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/my-waking-up/truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 09:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/my-waking-up/truth/</guid>
      <description>How do I know what is true and what is false? This is a surprisingly deep question, and surprisingly few people ever think much about it. Or then again, perhaps it isn&amp;rsquo;t surprising. Whether we are aware of it or not we all have mental machinery humming along that helps us make the countless choices we need to make. Most of us instinctually recognize that messing with this machinery might cause a person&amp;rsquo;s life to break down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deeper</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/my-waking-up/deeper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 09:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/my-waking-up/deeper/</guid>
      <description>In my thirties I ended up in a lot of pain. I longed for a release from this pain, and on a subconscious level suicide might even have been starting to look attractive. At least it all would be over then. I tried talk therapy, but was deeply unimpressed with that method, although it seems to have worked for others. Then I stumbled onto some mildly radical personal growth seminars. I absolutely loved them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flaming Intellectual</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/my-waking-up/flaming-intellectual/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 09:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/my-waking-up/flaming-intellectual/</guid>
      <description>But I didn&amp;rsquo;t know all this when I was sitting back there on that picnic bench at U. of C. It took a long personal journey before I learned to trust other sources of knowledge other than pure reason. To most people this is hardly a discovery - my wife laughs that I was ever in doubt about it. But, I wish someone would have explained this to me when I was younger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limits of Reason</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/my-waking-up/limits-of-reason/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 09:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/my-waking-up/limits-of-reason/</guid>
      <description>In class we studied how formal reasoning works. It turns out that any formal reasoning system starts out with basic assumptions (called axioms) and works up from there. No useful logical system can be built without these assumptions, but these assumptions have to be taken on faith - they are outside of the system. So many arguments are pointless because the participants are starting with radically different assumptions. Given how enormously important our assumptions are, it is shocking how unaware we typically are of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other States</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/my-waking-up/other-states/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 09:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/my-waking-up/other-states/</guid>
      <description>Before I talked about Descartes&#39; (and my) assumption that the rational mind is the center and everything else, including our bodies, revolves around it. I now believe just the opposite - it is our bodies that are the center and everything else, including our rational minds, revolves around the body. The proof for this statement is not in thinking about it rationally, but to instead introspect and remember the states that you have been to, and to at least be open to the possibility of finding other states.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limits of Reason</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/my-waking-up/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 09:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/my-waking-up/now/</guid>
      <description>Life is a rich and varied banquet. Rationalists that stay safe in only their rational minds are missing out on the full richness of being human. When I try to talk about this with my rationalist friends it is somewhat frustrating - I end up basically saying, yes, pizza is one of my favorite foods too, but there is so much else out there as well, why not do a little more exploring?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/my-waking-up/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 09:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/posts/my-waking-up/resources/</guid>
      <description>Gödel Escher Bach By Douglas R. Hofstadter
If you feel like exploring your rational mind, this is definitely the book for you. This is the best book I&amp;rsquo;ve seen for explaining the rational method. Amongst his other themes Hofstadter does a great job of explaining Goedel&amp;rsquo;s theorem.   The Multi Orgasmic Couple By Mantak Chia and Maneen Chia, Douglas Abrams and Rachel Abrams.
In very down to earth practical terms shows how both men and women can focus their minds and bodies to achieve multiple orgasms.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
