<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blue Truth Work</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/blue_work/index.html</link>
    <description>One of the core gifts of Blue is spirituality so I’m going to talk a lot about it. But different people mean different things when they use that word. I love Brene Brown’s definition:&#xA;Spirituality is recognizing and celebrating that we are all inextricably connected to one another by a power greater than all of us, and that our connection to that power and to one another is grounded in love and belonging. Practicing spirituality brings a sense of perspective, meaning and purpose to our lives</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 05:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/waking-up/blue_work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nonviolence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/blue_work/non-violence/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/blue_work/non-violence/index.html</guid>
      <description>Let’s go all the way back to the time of Jesus. Some Christians insist he was the son of God as if that isn’t true for all of us. No, he was just a dude. But oh my what an enormous impact he had on the world. Please don’t hold against him the many later crimes committed in his name. Let’s go back to the time when Christianity was just starting.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bigger Truth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/blue_work/truth/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/blue_work/truth/index.html</guid>
      <description>How do we know something is True? When I ask people this question, I can almost literally see their eyes roll all the way up into their heads. Does this seem like some weird esoteric question not related to day to day reality? It really is not — it is one the very most important questions you can choose to ask yourself. Because when you ask this question you start to notice what fundamental assumptions you have. We tend not to think about them, but we really should. For me my starting assumption was that only rationality could get me to Truth. But as I started to really pay attention to how the world works I realized that is a limiting belief. It won’t get me all to all the Truth that is out there. I will always honor and cherish my rationality. It is an important path to Truth, but it is not the only one. There are others. How do you find them? You have to experience them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mindfulness</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/blue_work/mindfulness/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/blue_work/mindfulness/index.html</guid>
      <description>Despite the angel’s kiss I didn’t suddenly declare myself spiritual. After the power and glory of that moment, I tried to go back to my life as a software engineer. A life that did not have any room for spirit in it. Even though I now had overwhelming evidence of spirit, it was just too much. I packed it into a box and stacked it way, way back in the closet of my mind. But bits and pieces of it kept on leaking out. And then more. I knew on some level that I was not an atheist any more but I didn’t really want to think about it. It was too much. Over many years (this would have been greatly speed up if I had just done the process consciously) occasionally my spiritual intuitions came up. And eventually I just started to allow them. Maybe not for very long, but I started to just allow that I had now another way of looking at the world. Then I let myself start to investigate what these spiritual longings were all about, and the fear that came up with them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mind/Body</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/blue_work/mind-body/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/blue_work/mind-body/index.html</guid>
      <description>Jill Bolte Taylor is a brain scientist who had a severe stroke in the left hemisphere of her brain. She wrote about her experience in the book, “My Stroke of Insight”.&#xA;The scientist in her got to watch in fascination as the impact of the stroke made itself known. What surprised her the most was the profound sense of peace and euphoria she experienced. Instead of feeling panic or fear, she was surprised to find herself immersed in a state of bliss and tranquility. She felt a deep sense of unity with the universe and a release from the worries and stresses because the left part of her brain that managed all that was no longer online. Please note that the left brain/right brain dichotomy turns out to maybe be a vast oversimplification of things. So please don’t get too hung up about that. What is important to note here is that there are in fact areas of the brain that do focus on one function or the other.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organicity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/blue_work/organicity/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/blue_work/organicity/index.html</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Change</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/blue_work/change/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/blue_work/change/index.html</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/blue_work/unity/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/blue_work/unity/index.html</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Loving Presence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/blue_work/love/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/blue_work/love/index.html</guid>
      <description>Gratitude Joy As you watch this, please consider standing up and dancing. And know that as you dance I dance with you and you are surrounded by so many others just letting themselves feel this all the way. Sometimes words just won’t do. You have to dance it out.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/blue_work/resources/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/blue_work/resources/index.html</guid>
      <description>Medicine How to Change Your Mind: What the New Science of Psychedelics Teaches Us About Consciousness, Dying, Addiction, Depression, and Transcendence by Michael Pollan.&#xA;This is such an important book. It has had a huge impact and reopened the flood gates to psychedelics. Medicine is a huge topic and I will come back to it in Green. But here it is sufficient to recognize what a powerful spiritual tool Medicine work can be.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Waking Up</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/blue_work/waking-up/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/blue_work/waking-up/index.html</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>