<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blue Truth Work on </title>
    <link>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/blue_work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blue Truth Work on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stwi.blog/waking-up/blue_work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nonviolence</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/blue_work/non-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/blue_work/non-violence/</guid>
      <description>Let’s go all the way back to the time of Jesus. Blue insists he was the son of God as if that isn’t true for all of us. No, he was just a dude. But oh my what an enormous impact he had on the world. Please don’t hold against him the many later crimes committed in his name. Let’s go back to the time when Christianity was just starting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bigger Truth</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/blue_work/truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/blue_work/truth/</guid>
      <description>How do we know something is True? This is such an important, fundamental question and yet I don’t see people thinking about it. I used to believe that only rationality could get me to Truth. Now I realize that while I will always honor and cherish my rationality, it is only one path to Truth. There are others.
In my mid thirties, I developed a very dangerous, painful tumor in my spinal column.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mindfulness</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/blue_work/mindfulness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/blue_work/mindfulness/</guid>
      <description>Despite the angel’s kiss I didn’t suddenly declare myself spiritual. So how did I start to awaken? After the power and glory of that moment, I tried to go back to my life as a software engineer. A life that did not have any room for spirit in it. Even though I now had overwhelming evidence of spirit, it was just too much. I packed it into a box and stacked it way, way back in the closet of my mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mind/Body</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/blue_work/mind-body/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/blue_work/mind-body/</guid>
      <description>As I deepened into my spiritual awakening it felt so amazing that I wanted to share. I wanted others to also find this place of joy inside themselves. But how? Religion works for some, but not for many others. We need something else. And then I did my first guided mushroom trip. Yes. This is a possible path. Spirit is not something you can just know in your mind, you have to actually feel it in your body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organicity</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/blue_work/organicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/blue_work/organicity/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/blue_work/change/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/blue_work/change/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/blue_work/unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/blue_work/unity/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loving Presence</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/blue_work/love/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/blue_work/love/</guid>
      <description>Gratitude Joy As you watch this, please consider standing up and dancing. And know that as you dance I dance with you and you are surrounded by so many others just letting themselves feel this all the way. Sometimes words just won’t do. You have to dance it out.
The reason I’m writing this document is joy. It is available to us all — I so long for everyone to find their way here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/blue_work/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/blue_work/resources/</guid>
      <description>Medicine How to Change Your Mind: What the New Science of Psychedelics Teaches Us About Consciousness, Dying, Addiction, Depression, and Transcendence by Michael Pollan.
This is such an important book. It has had a huge impact and reopened the flood gates to psychedelics. Medicine is a huge topic and I will come back to it in Green. But here it is sufficient to recognize what a powerful spiritual tool Medicine work can be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waking Up</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/blue_work/waking-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/waking-up/blue_work/waking-up/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
