<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spiral Dynamics on Save The World</title>
    <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/spiral-dynamics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spiral Dynamics on Save The World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/spiral-dynamics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Beige</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/spiral-dynamics/beige/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/spiral-dynamics/beige/</guid>
      <description>Beige  Color Nickname Social construct Cause worth dying for  Beige FirstAwakening Family and Kin My family   In the very beginning, our ancestors somehow had the first awakening. We stepped into a stage of consciousness higher than other animals. Imagine a caveman dad sitting on a rock with his son looking up at the full moon. The son says &amp;ldquo;Dad, what is that?&amp;rdquo;, And the dad says, &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Purple</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/spiral-dynamics/purple/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/spiral-dynamics/purple/</guid>
      <description>Color Nickname Social construct Cause worth dying for  Purple KinSpirits Tribe The sacred ground   Something amazing happened about 30,000 to 40,000 years ago. We see it in the cave paintings of the time. When we stop and really look at this powerful art we can not help but be moved. These people were just like us. This was clearly the next step up in consciousness. From smallish bands we formed bigger tribes and we became bad-asses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/spiral-dynamics/red/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/spiral-dynamics/red/</guid>
      <description>Color Nickname Social construct Cause worth dying for  Red PowerGods Kingdoms, Empire My king. Honor   This is the stage of empire. The strong ruled over the weak. We are taught to venerate Rome, but by today&amp;rsquo;s standards it was a hopelessly evil slave empire. It was very Red. Rulers the world over declared themself as God. The Pharoahs built their pyramids and other rulers demanded that their followers commit suicide when they died.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blue</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/spiral-dynamics/blue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/spiral-dynamics/blue/</guid>
      <description>table tr#Blue td {background-color:#00BFFF !important;}   Color Nickname Social construct Cause worth dying for  Blue TrueBlue Church,Schools The Truth   There is a Truth that is eternal and greater than us. This is what we wake up to in the Blue stage. We surrender to something bigger than us. And that surrender brings a profound, sweet purpose and meaning to life. Before this, Truth was localized. Whoever had the most power and authority determined what Truth was.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/spiral-dynamics/orange/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/spiral-dynamics/orange/</guid>
      <description>Color Nickname Social construct Cause worth dying for  Orange StriveDrive Capitalism, Democracy, and Science Give me liberty or give me death   The Japanese were confronting the technological results of The Age of Enlightenment. This was a turn away from the church and God towards looking for the Truth within. From this stage emerged modern science, capitalism, and democracy. America&amp;rsquo;s Declaration of Independence is a quintessential expression of Orange:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/spiral-dynamics/green/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/spiral-dynamics/green/</guid>
      <description>table tr#Green td {background-color:#228B22;}   Color Nickname Social construct Cause worth dying for  Green HumanBond unions, environmentalism, feminism, racial justice, LGBTQ, et. al For my brothers and sisters   The genius of Martin Luther King&amp;rsquo;s I have a dream speech is that it builds on the (Orange) words of the Declaration of Independence and brings us forward into a new stage, Green.
 &amp;ldquo;I have a dream that one day this nation will rise up and live out the true meaning of its creed - we hold these truths to be self-evident: that all men are created equal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yellow</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/spiral-dynamics/yellow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/spiral-dynamics/yellow/</guid>
      <description>Color Nickname Social construct Cause worth dying for  Yellow SecondAwakening Integral Theory, personal growth movement, medicine movement A life worth living   At some point we need to turn back to ourselves to find the Truth of things. We have absorbed the lessons of Green, and yet we are not at peace with ourselves. Green by itself won&amp;rsquo;t get us to the healing we need. Green by itself won&amp;rsquo;t heal the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turquoise</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/spiral-dynamics/turquoise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/growing-up/spiral-dynamics/turquoise/</guid>
      <description>Color Nickname Social construct Cause worth dying for  Turqoise PromisedLand Just starting to emerge Save the world   After finding our vast strength in Yellow we start to really open up to all that is. And it hurts. Really hurts. The world is suffering in so many needless ways. We have met this pain before and run away, but this time we suddenly realize how truly big we are.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
