<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome on Save The World</title>
    <link>https://turquoise-community.github.io/save-the-world/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welcome on Save The World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 12:55:04 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://turquoise-community.github.io/save-the-world/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stone Soup1</title>
      <link>https://turquoise-community.github.io/save-the-world/stone-soup/stone-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 10:04:31 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://turquoise-community.github.io/save-the-world/stone-soup/stone-soup/</guid>
      <description>Stone Soup &amp;ndash; stone soup text goes here &amp;mdash; edited</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>https://turquoise-community.github.io/save-the-world/welcome/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 10:04:31 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://turquoise-community.github.io/save-the-world/welcome/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Welcome! Thank you so much visiting this web site! I&amp;rsquo;m just at the very beginning of this project and I need all the help I can get to make this something that serves.
Know that it was very hard for me to ask you to come visit something that is so rough and unfinished. I truly am deeply grateful that you did! Please also know that I will treasure any feedback you can give me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Index</title>
      <link>https://turquoise-community.github.io/save-the-world/articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 11:36:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://turquoise-community.github.io/save-the-world/articles/</guid>
      <description>Home
 Welcome and thanks Saving the world  Pain of the world   There is hope  Acknowledge hopelessness theory advances psychological advances medicine advances spiritual advances      The dream
 Mr. Roger&amp;rsquo;s neighborhood  we already know let the children guide us Generational trauma  protect the children stop the cycle (or at least dampen it)     Big dream  New groups, new ways of organizing Not saints &amp;ndash; a practice Spiritual awakening  reclaiming spirituality joy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Save the World</title>
      <link>https://turquoise-community.github.io/save-the-world/posts/save-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 16:16:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://turquoise-community.github.io/save-the-world/posts/save-the-world/</guid>
      <description>I love movies where the reluctant heroes are desperately trying to save the world against what seem impossible odds. First they overcome their fears and limitations, and then they commit. Then they work through their bitter squabbles and commit to each other. I want to be like them. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping you do too, because the world is in desperate need of heroes right now.
Police kill black men seemingly at will.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spheres of compassion</title>
      <link>https://turquoise-community.github.io/save-the-world/posts/we-need-a-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 16:16:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://turquoise-community.github.io/save-the-world/posts/we-need-a-plan/</guid>
      <description>But first we need a plan. Our current approach is not working. There are many things not working, but let me focus on climate change because it is a huge problem. Emissions keep on going up. World wide agreements are made, but never for enough and emissions keep on going up. Environmentalists pin their hope on elections but then the other party gets elected and dismantles previous work. And emissions keep on going up.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
