<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome on Save The World</title>
    <link>https://example.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welcome on Save The World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 12:55:04 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stone Soup1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/stone-soup/stone-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 10:04:31 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/stone-soup/stone-soup/</guid>
      <description>Stone Soup &amp;ndash; stone soup text goes here &amp;mdash; edited</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>https://example.com/welcome/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 10:04:31 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/welcome/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Welcome! 2 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Index</title>
      <link>https://example.com/articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 11:36:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/articles/</guid>
      <description>Home  Welcome and thanks there is hope  theory advances psychological advances medicine advances spiritual advances     The dream  Mr. Roger&amp;rsquo;s neighborhood  we already know let the children guide us   Big dream  New groups Not saints &amp;ndash; a practice Spiritual awakening  joy!     Same goal Deadline Generational trauma  protect the children   All of us  Integral Love     Who am I  All of me Software engineer path (very brief version)  Radical truth  Running in debug mode Embrace when you are wrong   Deep dive  Five whys   Models Open source   Personal growth Spirit   Stone soup  Stone soup story First steps  Believe it is possible Believe we are worthy of a bigger dream Practical plan   I need your help RFC Open Source  Shared libraries Forking Copyright     The Plan  Definition of success  All of Us Joy   Need for models  Challenger disaster  Sneaky switch   Beyond stupid and evil   Overview  Patterns of history: What wants to happen next Reclaiming spirituality     Patterns of history  Spiral Dynamics  History  My take &amp;ndash; social constructs Beige Purple  Spirit   Red  Empire  Alexander the Great, Attilla the Hun Columbus   Olympics  personal excellence     Blue  Jesus and Mohammed Neo Confucianism  Attilla goes from red to blue   Martin Luther King and Gandhi   Orange  Enlightenment Black ships   Green  Reaction to Reason Hakomi principles Difference between Blue   Yellow  Hakomi HAI Medicine  How to change your mind  Michael Pollan needed green to get here     Maps example   Turquoise  Showing up     Tick-Tock  Oscillation America doesn&amp;rsquo;t get group focus  My Japan experience (?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Save the World</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/save-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 16:16:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/save-the-world/</guid>
      <description>I love movies where the reluctant heroes are desperately trying to save the world against what seem impossible odds. First they overcome their fears and limitations, and then they commit. Then they work through their bitter squabbles and commit to each other. I want to be like them. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping you do too, because the world is in desperate need of heroes right now.
Police kill black men seemingly at will.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spheres of compassion</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/we-need-a-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 16:16:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/we-need-a-plan/</guid>
      <description>But first we need a plan. Our current approach is not working. There are many things not working, but let me focus on climate change because it is a huge problem. Emissions keep on going up. World wide agreements are made, but never for enough and emissions keep on going up. Environmentalists pin their hope on elections but then the other party gets elected and dismantles previous work. And emissions keep on going up.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
