<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome!</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/index.html</link>
    <description>“Hope is not blind optimism. It’s not ignoring the enormity of the task ahead or the roadblocks that stand in our path. It’s not sitting on the sidelines or shirking from a fight. Hope is that thing inside us that insists, despite all evidence to the contrary, that something better awaits us if we have the courage to reach for it, and to work for it, and to fight for it. Hope is the belief that destiny will not be written for us, but by us, by the men and women who are not content to settle for the world as it is, who have the courage to remake the world as it should be.”</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Dream</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-dream/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-dream/index.html</guid>
      <description>Let’s start. May I have your permission to dream with me? Dream way, way, way bigger than you maybe normally do? OK? Here is my question: What do you really want? I mean really. Yes, yes you can have a billion dollars – boom – now keep on going deeper. This is a dream after all so you can have anything. What do you want beyond just the superficial stuff? Maybe deep happiness for yourself? Yes, please hold on to that part of the dream, but try going even a little further. Maybe dream of happiness for others? Certainly you can dream of happiness for your loved ones, but how about living in a world of joy for all? Wait, you can imagine a billion dollars but not that? Stay with me here. Let’s try again. Stop and breathe. Settle down into your body. Notice where you are and everything you are feeling in this moment right now. And then ask yourself the question again, but this time from your heart. What is the biggest dream you can dream? How wide can you open your heart? Notice if resistance comes up. That is very normal. Take a breath again and see what is going on. Is the resistance still there? Try to really get in touch with what this is about. Know this is our core work – it is going to guide us on what needs to happen. Just about all of us are working on expanding our hearts past this resistance. I don’t think we ever are done with this work. And we all can use teachers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Growing Up</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/growing-up/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/growing-up/index.html</guid>
      <description>In this section I am going to tell a story. A story of where we have been and where we are right now. A story that is unfinished but with strong hints of what wants to happen next.&#xA;I know a bit about the power of finding the right story because I named myself based on one (The Odyssey). Finding the right story transforms and strengthens. Makes things clearer. Gives courage and a direction. We all need to find our own story. The reason why we came to earth. But we also need to find our shared story. What is it that we are meant to do together?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cleaning Up</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cleaning-up/index.html</guid>
      <description>if people are too much in pain, they are not available for doing anything else. Cleaning Up shows how we can step out of pain and into connection with others. It shows the healing power of nature and community. It takes on all our traumas, and starts to transform them into something we can live with. We have to start here.&#xA;If you haven’t watched the stink spirit video from Spirited Away yet please consider watching it now. It is such a good metaphor for this work.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Waking Up</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/waking-up/index.html</guid>
      <description>“Cleaning Up” is a good foundation to build on. But it is just the foundation. Let’s see what we can build on top of it.&#xA;“Waking Up” combines the fierce ambition to conquer the world with the grace of surrendering to something bigger than ourselves. Think of Martin Luther King. He came from a place of righteous anger that would not be turned aside, but he led us to a place of much bigger love. That is what “Waking Up” brings to the world. We need more of this. So far not so bad, but it gets harder. I’m also going to ask you to embrace your inner asshole and encourage you to step out on to the skinniest branches of woo woo. Easy right?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Showing Up</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/showing-up/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/showing-up/index.html</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/resources/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/resources/index.html</guid>
      <description>Save The World Books This is a list of the books that have a plan to save the world. There are surprisingly few of them. Most are not well known.&#xA;Community Peter Block works with communities to help them find their voice and power. This book is a guide to what seems to work the best. Val Hammel is using this as a guide to how she can revitalize HAI and make it flourish. She thinks the way to save the world is to rebuild our communities. I strongly agree with her.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wising Up</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/wising-up/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/wising-up/index.html</guid>
      <description>Back to where we started Different Story Healing Unity Dream! Why it is now possible better model reclaiming spirituality healing and growth Boddhisatva vow Goals Healing Focus on what works Generational trauma – stop hurting children Working with all the colors add the missing blue helping people to find Turqoise What is working HAI CSL MSC NVC Hakomi RAIN Cohousing Very green! better ways to raise our children consensus as a personal growth mechanism Medicine Church of personal growth Establish practices (like karate does) Bring up our own leaders Build in feedback Address fear of doing harm Leader as servant mentality Governance Need for new governance. Sociocracy? Accountable Evangelical</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Other Articles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/other/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 05:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/other/index.html</guid>
      <description>This section contains other articles.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 10:04:31 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/index.html</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Articles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/index.html</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>