<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Dream</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/the-dream/index.html</link>
    <description>Let’s start. May I have your permission to dream with me? Dream way, way, way bigger than you maybe normally do? OK? Here is my question: What do you really want? I mean really. Yes, yes you can have a billion dollars – boom – now keep on going deeper. This is a dream after all so you can have anything. What do you want beyond just the superficial stuff? Maybe deep happiness for yourself? Yes, please hold on to that part of the dream, but try going even a little further. Maybe dream of happiness for others? Certainly you can dream of happiness for your loved ones, but how about living in a world of joy for all? Wait, you can imagine a billion dollars but not that? Stay with me here. Let’s try again. Stop and breathe. Settle down into your body. Notice where you are and everything you are feeling in this moment right now. And then ask yourself the question again, but this time from your heart. What is the biggest dream you can dream? How big can you open your heart? Notice if resistance comes up. That is very normal. Take a breath again and see what is going on. Is the resistance still there? Try to really get in touch with what this is about. Know this is our core work – it is going to guide us on what needs to happen. Just about all of us are working on expanding our hearts past this resistance. I don’t think we ever are done with this work. And we all can use teachers.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/the-dream/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Who Am I?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-dream/who-am-i/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-dream/who-am-i/index.html</guid>
      <description>Who am I to save the world? I am just some guy on the internet. I don’t have any particular expertise or credentials. But in some ways this ordinariness is actually an advantage. I am not some exalted leader to be revered. If I can do this work anyone can. There is no particular reason you should listen to me other than maybe I can get you to think.&#xA;At first I tried to keep myself out of this essay, but what I have to offer is myself. Not just the shiny parts I want to show to you, but all of my rage, sorrow and pain too. Not just the gifts that I have, but the broken hurting places too. To give this any chance of working I can’t hold anything back. I need to bring in everything that I am. All of me is sacred and holy. All is welcome and loved.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Learnings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-dream/discoveries/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-dream/discoveries/index.html</guid>
      <description>Community Living in Japan and married to a Japanese woman really opened my eyes to community. I experienced culture shock twice in Japan. The first time was on first arriving there. Everything was so different, and I had never been to a truly foreign country before. It was a comparatively mild shock. The second, much bigger shock happened a year later just as my Japanese was starting to get good enough to give me a glimpse of how truly different the Japanese look at the world. I woke up to how I just assumed there was only one world view. I really thought everyone looked at the world the way Americans do. That is so not true! The Japanese do not view the world as a bunch of individuals making their way, they instead see the world through a much, much more group focus. The purpose of life is not just a selfish pursuit of individual happiness. I don’t think either the American or Japanese perspective is wrong. From what I could tell there is a mix of profound benefits and costs to each. But what it did was to open my eyes to how differently people can view this world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Systems Thinking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-dream/going-deeper/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-dream/going-deeper/index.html</guid>
      <description>If you walk into a bookstore you will find books on saving yourself, but not on saving the world. You will find books addressing specific problems, but not on how all these problems relate together as a whole. There are a few books like that of course. I have made a point of finding them. But they are not well known and definitely not best sellers. Why is that? Why don’t we have even one well known plan to save the world? Partly because it is just too overwhelming. We are all stuck in the trance of helplessness. Our shared story is still way too small. But another part is that most of us don’t have much experience working with complex systems. Some people do though – for example programmers. We have to. No one ever formally taught me how to manage complex systems, but out of necessity I learned it over time. I learned that any problem at its heart is because people are far from perfect and you have to figure out how to compensate for our human weaknesses. It turns out that is true of all our problems, not just computer ones. Later on I discovered there is a name for this kind of thinking. It is called Systems Thinking. It recognizes that when you are dealing with the “wicked problems” of the world you first have to understand the whole system. The temptation is to just pick a part of the problem and get to work because the need is so urgent, but that ultimately has limits. It can help, but it will not get us all the way where we want. We need to go deeper. We need to use systems thinking. It is the only thing that works. So how does this method work? Let me give some examples.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Source</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-dream/open-source/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-dream/open-source/index.html</guid>
      <description>More people should be aware of the open source movement. It is kind of a big deal. I’ve been watching it with fascination from the beginning. In the 1990’s it was not at all clear that it would end up completely conquering the world, but it did. Much of the software that you are using at this very moment is open source. It is built into the very foundations of the internet. Open Source out competed fierce capitalistic companies because it is a better way of collaborating. It is the only instance that I know of where communism won. No one owns open source software; people freely donate their time to it as a gift to the world. Ideas work best when they are free. And frameworks work best when many people have taken a serious look at them and offered improvements. But despite this idealism open source exists to be of use. Not all contributions are accepted. It is not like the wikipedia where there are endless, wasteful edit wars over controversial topics. Open source tends to avoid all that and stays focused on delivering value. And if it doesn’t, some other open source project comes along to replace it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guidelines</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-dream/guidelines/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-dream/guidelines/index.html</guid>
      <description>I suggest we run this site the way open source projects usually are run. Programmers kind of just know how it works but let me try and make the underlying principles clear here. The goal is to come up with guidelines that we can fall back on when we are trying to decide what goes in and what stays out. Something that guides us as we write and review. If you find that some part of this site does not match these guidelines please let me know - it is a bug that needs to be fixed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-dream/overview/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-dream/overview/index.html</guid>
      <description>So how are we going to do this? What does the plan look like?&#xA;The Goal First we need to be clear on where we are going. What do we truly want for this world? What would light us up all the way? I suggested earlier that we don’t have to over think this. Let our love for our children guide us. Let our inner child guide us. We already know what we dream for the world, we just have to dare to believe it is possible. On some beautiful day the world is going to wake up in love and joy. But we can’t just jump straight there from where we are now. This is where the work is.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>