<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Dream on Save The World</title>
    <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/the-dream/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Dream on Save The World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/the-dream/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>We need a plan</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/the-dream/we-need-a-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/the-dream/we-need-a-plan/</guid>
      <description>All of me, All of you, All of us. If I&amp;rsquo;m going to propose something so audacious as a plan to save the world, it is going to require all of me. I can&amp;rsquo;t hold anything back. I need to bring in everything that I am. Not just the shiny parts I want to show to you, but all of my rage, sorrow and pain too. Not just the gifts that I have, but the broken hurting places too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Am I?</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/the-dream/who-am-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/the-dream/who-am-i/</guid>
      <description>Before I can go further, I think it is necessary to talk a little about myself first. Who is this person dreaming such a big dream? What particular viewpoint am I coming from?
I&amp;rsquo;m a 58 year old white male living in the Bay Area. I have two kids (Ulysses and Jaiya) from separate marriages and they are the world to me. I&amp;rsquo;ve been a software programmer most of my life, and I love programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/the-dream/open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/the-dream/open-source/</guid>
      <description>More people should be aware of the open source movement. It is kind of a big deal. I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching it with fascination from the beginning. In the 1990&amp;rsquo;s it was not at all clear that it would end up completely conquering the world. But it did. Much of the software that you are using at this very moment is open source. It is built into the very foundations of the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/the-dream/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/the-dream/overview/</guid>
      <description>Here is a very high level overview of the plan.
The Goal First we need to be clear on where we are going. What do we truly want for this world? What would light us up all the way? I suggested earlier that we don&amp;rsquo;t have to overthink this. Let the children guide us. And in particular, let our inner child guide us. We already know what we dream for the world, we just have to dare to believe it is possible.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
