<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Dream on </title>
    <link>https://stwi.blog/the-dream/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Dream on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://stwi.blog/the-dream/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Who Am I?</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/the-dream/who-am-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/the-dream/who-am-i/</guid>
      <description>Who am I to save the world? I am just some guy on the internet. I don&amp;rsquo;t have any particular expertise or credentials. There is no particular reason you should listen to me other than maybe I can get you to think. But in some ways this ordinariness is actually an advantage. I am not some exalted leader to be revered. If I can do this work anyone can.
At first I tried to keep myself out of this essay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systems Thinking</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/the-dream/going-deeper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/the-dream/going-deeper/</guid>
      <description>If you walk into a bookstore you will find books on saving yourself, but not on saving the world. You will find books addressing specific problems, but not on how all these problems relate together as a whole. There are a few books like that of course. I have made a point of finding them. But they are not well known and definitely not best sellers. Why is that? Why don&amp;rsquo;t we have even one well known plan to save the world?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Am I?</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/the-dream/discoveries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/the-dream/discoveries/</guid>
      <description>Community Living in Japan and married to a Japanese woman really opened my eyes to community. I experienced culture shock twice in Japan. The first time was on first arriving there. Everything was so different, and I had never been to a truly foreign country before. It was a comparatively mild shock. The second, much bigger shock happened a year later just as my Japanese was starting to get good enough to give me a glimpse of how truly different the Japanese look at the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/the-dream/open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/the-dream/open-source/</guid>
      <description>More people should be aware of the open source movement. It is kind of a big deal. I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching it with fascination from the beginning. In the 1990&amp;rsquo;s it was not at all clear that it would end up completely conquering the world, but it did. Much of the software that you are using at this very moment is open source. It is built into the very foundations of the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guidelines</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/the-dream/guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/the-dream/guidelines/</guid>
      <description>I suggest we run this site the way open source projects usually are run. Programmers kind of just know how it works but let me try and make the underlying principles clear here. The goal is to come up with guidelines that we can fall back on when we are trying to decide what goes in and what stays out. Something that guides us as we write and review. If you find that some part of this site does not match these guidelines please let me know - it is a bug that needs to be fixed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>https://stwi.blog/the-dream/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stwi.blog/the-dream/overview/</guid>
      <description>So how are we going to do this? What does the plan look like?
The Goal First we need to be clear on where we are going. What do we truly want for this world? What would light us up all the way? I suggested earlier that we don&amp;rsquo;t have to over think this. Let our love for our children guide us. Let our inner child guide us. We already know what we dream for the world, we just have to dare to believe it is possible.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
