<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Dream on Save The World</title>
    <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/the-dream/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Dream on Save The World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/the-dream/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Who Am I?</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/the-dream/who-am-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/the-dream/who-am-i/</guid>
      <description>Before I can go further, I think it is necessary to talk a little about myself. When I first started writing this I hoped that I could mostly keep myself out of this document because obviously this is about so much more than just me. I am just this nobody on the internet. I am not some expert giving an authoritative report. I am just this guy trying to start a conversation about something I passionately care about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/the-dream/open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/the-dream/open-source/</guid>
      <description>More people should be aware of the open source movement. It is kind of a big deal. I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching it with fascination from the beginning. In the 1990&amp;rsquo;s it was not at all clear that it would end up completely conquering the world, but it did. Much of the software that you are using at this very moment is open source. It is built into the very foundations of the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principles</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/the-dream/guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/the-dream/guidelines/</guid>
      <description>Let me suggest a set of guiding principles for this project. Something that we can fall back on when we are trying to decide what goes in and what stays out. Something that guides us as we write and review. If you find that some part of this site does not match these principles please let me know - it is a bug that needs to be fixed.
Simplicity I deeply value your time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/the-dream/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cosmosgame.github.io/save-the-world/the-dream/overview/</guid>
      <description>Here is a very high level overview of the plan.
The Goal First we need to be clear on where we are going. What do we truly want for this world? What would light us up all the way? I suggested earlier that we don&amp;rsquo;t have to overthink this. Let our love for our children guide us. Let our inner child guide us. We already know what we dream for the world, we just have to dare to believe it is possible.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
